Alejandro Romo UX/FE Engineer

https://github.com/ale-romo

Profile

Highly-skilled Front-End Engineer with a multidisciplinary background. Expert at creating web experiences that exceed user expectations, support business objectives and uphold engineering best practices.

Skills

Tech proficiency

Next Js, React, Typescript, Webpack, Jest, RTL, HTML, JSX, CSS, Sass, Tailwind, Styled components, CSS Modules, Github, Vercel, StoryBook, Chromatic, AWS, Jenkins.

Cultural and organizational

Bilingual (ESP, ENG), Agile, Literate in UX, Marketing, and Business.

Professional Experience

Senior Front End Developer, Nebulosa Studio

2022/09 - 2023/05 | Vancouver, Canada

- Spearheaded the refinement of development processes and introduced a component-driven UI development approach, enhancing code reusability and scalability.
- Implemented Storybook and Chromatic, advancing UI testing and review processes.
- Fostered consistent quality control, contributing to improved accessibility, performance, and increased accuracy while estimating project milestones.

Front End Software Engineer, Intuit

2016 – 2021 | San Diego, United States

- Collaborated as part of the TurboTax marketing website team to develop a flexible, high-performing React-based product comparison experience. This robust solution seamlessly integrated with Intuit's testing platform and was architected to support rapid iterations for key marketing learnings ahead of peak season, while maintaining stability for up to 500,000 simultaneous users.
- Pioneered the development of a component library and a custom CMS, empowering copywriters to create experiences independently of the engineering team.
- Played a key role onboarding the Marketing and Authentication teams onto a centralized UX component library which enabled them to focus on their core responsibilities while UX concerns were managed by the central team.

Founder/Engineer, Mint IT Media

2009 - present | Tijuana, Mexico

- Co-founded Mint IT Media, a development studio that created custom web applications for local businesses and marketing websites for the clients of high-end Design and Branding companies.
- Successfully guided clients in shifting from traditional brick-and-mortar and print frameworks to adopting robust online service infrastructures.
- Initiated and launched self-funded web applications such as Garita Center, an app for tracking border crossing times, among many others.
- Developed an infrastructure/community that allows me to pick up small freelance projects between professional contracts.

Media Engineering Professor, CETYS University ☑

2012/08 - 2016/12 | Tijuana, Mexico

- Advocated for curriculum updates to mirror evolving industry requirements, successfully replacing 'Operating Systems' with 'Web Project Development' to introduce students to contemporary Front End Development.
- Designed and executed an immersive learning project, "Instarally," requiring students to create a web application, engage the community, and analyze project success using real-world metrics, fostering a result-driven development mindset.
- Collaborated in the rewriting of multiple subjects for the Web Development track in the program's third iteration (2015), aligning the curriculum with the latest industry standards.

Education

MBA, CETYS University 🛮

2015 | Tijuana, Mexico

UX/Media Engineering, CETYS University ☑

2009 | Tijuana, Mexico